How is Rafilia?
She's fine.
She was probably tense this whole time.
She fell asleep.
Brother, sorry for worrying you.
No need to thank me.
I'm glad your daughter is safe.
Yes.
RAVISEL'S INTENTIONS
Is Rafilia all right?
Yes.
She's uninjured, and perhaps because
she now feels safe, she's fast asleep.
Anyway, you and Mother were so cool, Father!
What's this all of a sudden?
Have you guys always been like that?
Their power was every bit as
astonishing as my father said it was!
That's the first I'm hearing of this!
Mother!
Vint said that?
Oh, he should have just told me himself.
Perhaps Vint is a bit shy, huh?
I'm not sure... Perhaps so.
Still, it's been so long that
I wasn't certain how much force to use.
Well, you can summon me anytime, you know?
That's true.
My skills will get rusty if I don't use spirit
magic with you once in a while, Ori.
Were my parents this amazing in the past too?
Oh, most certainly.
Once, the knights were ordered
to apprehend some bandits.
The bandits were trying to use tamed
wolves to harry our forces.
Wolves?
Yes. Lord Rovel, who caught on
to our enemy's scheme,
immediately summoned Lady Origin. And then...
And then?!
Those ferocious wolves turned as docile
as puppies before Lady Origin.
Next, Lord Rovel used spirit magic
that was like a tornado
to lift the bandits and wolves into the air,
then slammed them back down
to earth, immobilizing them.
The poor wolves...
Thanks to your parents, it was
very easy to apprehend them.
As expected from Lord Rovel and the queen!
Wait, magic that was like a tornado?
Father.
You usually use ice magic,
but you can use wind magic as well?
I can, as long as Ori is nearby.
She can conjure
all of the elements, after all.
Makes sense!
Besides, my pact with your mother is the
only reason I can use magic in the first place.
Oh, I see.
But don't you go making pacts
with just anybody, okay, Ellen?
Yes, ma'am!
Ellen, you don't have to make
a pact with anyone, okay?
What?
Goodness, Rovel. You're so narrow-minded.
Come on!
Father, I can't breathe!
Come in.
Lady Rafilia has awakened.
Rafilia.
Gadiel!
I'm glad you're safe.
Your Highness.
Let us talk details tomorrow.
Understood. Well then, if you'll excuse me.
Gadiel, thank you for worrying about me.
Sure.
So you're Ellen.
Yes. It's nice to meet you, Rafi—
It's all your fault!
It's your fault I got put in this mess!
You're horrible!
Rafilia.
But—
You were targeted because you were
already exchanging letters with the prince.
Ellen had nothing to do with it.
Why is it always like this?
All people talk about is Ellen!
I'm a daughter of the Vankreift
family too, you know?
Is that... how you've felt all this time?
You got a problem with me or something?!
What? I was just trying to help out
the Vankreift family for my father.
And... I'm really sorry about what happened.
Hmph! Gadiel said he wanted
to see you too, but...
Are you really the same age as me?
Huh?
You're small in more ways than one.
What do you mean?
Hmph!
Th-They'll get bigger!
What, starting now?
Don't ya think it's a bit late for that?
They'll grow big...
Your mother's are huge,
so you'll be fine, Ellen.
Father!
There, there. Yep, nothing to worry about.
A mere human speaking
so rudely to the princess...
I'll remember that.
Ellen, don't worry about it
and get some rest.
But...
Princess!
Shall I go tear that little girl to shreds?
Van?! No, don't do that!
Rafilia is my cousin.
Your cousin, you say?
Yes, so don't be mad.
I shall do my best.
Oh, I know!
Here, my princess!
Indulge in my fluff as you please!
Van!
Oh, fine already.
Join in, Father. Let's enjoy it together.
All right!
Fluffy, fluffy, fluffy, fluffy, fluffy fluff!
FLUFFY FLUFFY FLUFFY
I want to grow up fast...
Hey, Ellen. Why are you
in such a hurry to grow up?
There's no way to stop growing,
even as a spirit.
You'll be an adult eventually, no matter what.
So what's wrong with things as they are now?
You're making your dad feel lonely.
When you grow up,
you'll be leaving my side, you know?
That's... That's...
Father?
I don't want that!
Ellen, please don't ever get married!
Ouch... That hurt, Ellen.
Father, just what's gotten into you?
Do you feel better?
Yes, completely.
I'm happy to have you
and Mother as my parents.
How's Ellen?
She cried herself to sleep.
My apologies for Rafilia.
To have spoken to Ellen like that...
Yeah, well, Ellen thought nothing of it.
Except for the whole size thing.
Listen, I'm sorry.
You daughter got dragged into all this
because of us and the royal family.
No, think nothing of it.
In fact, I think things may have
turned out for the better.
It's a bit of an odd story,
but this incident has finally made me realize
why Rafilia's been so rebellious.
I now understand how she feels.
Well, I'm certain it's only
the tip of the iceberg, but...
That's important.
Yes.
Anyway, that was all exhausting!
It's been some time, hasn't it?
I wanted to join in and let loose myself,
I'll have you know!
To think I'd be guarding the
princess with a brat like you.
Are you displeased I was chosen?
Displeased, you say? You bet I am.
What can a brat like you even do?
I'm honored to be able
to work with a great spirit.
I cannot go to the spirit world,
so I think it's only natural that you
were selected to protect Lady Ellen.
But of course.
However, I believe that my desire
to protect her is no different than yours.
So I'm pleased to be working with you.
What is this?
It's the customary gesture humans use
to begin good working relationships.
Why greet me with a human custom?
If you plan on taking on a human form,
you'd do well to remember it.
Amazing!
Hey, stop that! My paws
are for the princess only!
This is how humans greet each other.
Quit lying!
Prince Gadiel has arrived.
Once again, I thank you
for your cooperation yesterday.
Rafilia has returned safely thanks to you.
Right.
Your Highness.
About this letter Rafilia received...
What are your thoughts on it?
It reads: "I will be visiting the
Vankreift domain on a mission.
If it's all right, could we meet?"
You're already aware that this
was sent from the royal family, yes?
As for the contents of the letter...
You must already have some idea
of who was responsible for it, don't you?
It could only be His Majesty.
I told him I was exchanging
letters with Rafilia, after all.
With this knowledge, His Majesty
sent you on a mission
to investigate the Vankreift domain.
His Majesty wanted to learn more
about our medicine
by involving you with me and my father,
all using Rafilia as bait.
That can't be...
Prince Gadiel, this is how
King Ravisel operates.
It's why I despise that man.
Well, this will serve as a test for you.
Rafilia was abducted on His Majesty's orders.
That is how we see it.
You're wrong! Those people had
no connection to the royal family!
Given the situation, it's only
natural for us to believe they did.
Or do you have some kind of proof?
Either way, we...
You didn't know.
That is what you were about to claim, yes?
Nevertheless, wouldn't you agree this is an
issue between us and the royal family?
Well... Yes. It is.
I'm glad to see that
we have an understanding.
Now, let us move on
to the subject of the medicine.
As promised, I will hand it
over to you, Your Highness.
Father, the medicine.
You can examine it, administer it,
do as you please with it.
Is there any way you could
teach us to make it?
Please, I beg you.
I cannot.
Don't say that.
I cannot give the royal family
the details of the medicine.
Even if I were to share with you
how to make it,
you would not understand.
What do you mean by that?
This medicine cannot
be produced in the human world.
What?
What did you say?
Granted, that doesn't mean spirits who live
in the spirit world can make it either.
Then what on earth is this medicine?!
I cannot tell you.
Why not try asking your spirit?
That's why you brought it, no?
Your Highness?
Ashute, if you could.
Well?
You don't know?
Hue, this is something that
doesn't exist in the human world.
So is it a medicine from the spirit world?
Spirits don't need medicine.
Then what about the ingredients?
Are they of the spirit world?
Don't think so. Ashu has never seen them before.
Then what in the world...
You cannot make that medicine.
We will supply it to you.
That's all there is to it.
That can't be...
Let us move along.
The medicine I just handed you
is called an antibiotic.
It kills the root of the disease,
but at the same time, it also kills
the good bacteria within the stomach.
You must keep taking the
medicine until the disease is gone,
but in exchange,
you may get terrible diarrhea.
This is what's known as a side effect.
A side effect?
Many things can cause illness.
A healer must determine which
based on the presented symptoms
and prescribe various medications.
Give thorough instructions
as to the precautions of each,
and ensure proper hygiene in the future.
Without these preventative measures,
we won't be able
to maintain the medicine supply,
Hume.
Y-Yes?
Would you please talk to our house healer
about how to handle the medicine?
Take all due care, as medicine can
become poison when handled incorrectly.
Understood.
Pawpaw, please show him there
if you'd be so kind.
It would be my pleasure.
Sir Hume, right this way.
Okay.
Your Highness.
We've given this first batch to you
in accordance with our promise,
but we will expect payment
for any future deliveries.
What?
This is the deal we're offering.
My apologies. I would like to consult
His Majesty on the matter first.
That's fine.
However, please inform him that we expect
terms that are satisfactory to us.
I shall.
Now then, let us return
to the original matter.
We shall be the ones to deal
with the men who kidnapped Rafilia.
Wait! We can't allow that!
Did you not state that they have
no connection to the royal family?
My father says that His Majesty likely
has proof that he isn't involved,
whether or not we hand them over.
So he should take no issue with this.
Well, that's...
I already warned you
to be prepared for what's to come.
Your Highness,
please relay this to His Majesty:
You will regret ever touching my family.
That is all.
P-Please wait!
What is it?
You said you'd hear me out.
If we manage to find Rafilia safely,
I ask that you please hear me out.
I believe I had your word.
Here, right now?
If not now, I have a feeling I'll never
have another chance to speak with you.
Would all of you please give us a moment?
Ellen, you plan on talking to him alone?
Is this something I can't stay for?
Father, please.
All right.
Listen, I'll say this one more time to be sure.
Do not approach Ellen.
I know.
Ellen, what we... What the royal
family did to the spirits...
Your Highness, you are part
of that royal family.
Your ancestors did something
they shouldn't have.
However, as a royal yourself, I'm sure that
you understand the reason
behind their actions.
At the time, the royal family sought
the spirits' power to protect the country.
But we still shouldn't have gone so far.
If you understand, then you of all people
should not be apologizing for it.
What? How could you say that?
Your ancestors had no regrets.
Whatever it meant for the royal family,
they intended to save their people from
the Monster Tempest two hundred years ago.
And that is how they went about it.
Still, the spirits didn't deserve...
They must have been so desperate
that it was their only option.
There is no undoing the sorrow
of the spirits sacrificed.
Because even though it is a thing
of the past for you royals,
to the eternal spirits,
it is as if it were only yesterday.
Still, I...
Your Highness, I have warned you.
You had best be prepared.
Yes.
I'm certain His Majesty heard
those cursed cries as well.
But in spite of that, he's dared
to lay a hand on my family.
The spreading of the disease
is gaining momentum.
Soon the royal capital will likely
be thrown into turmoil.
King Ravisel has taken us too lightly.
After all he's done, do not think
for a moment you will have our aid.
This is our final warning.
Please do not make contact with us ever again.
But... I...
I...
There's nothing more to talk about.
Ellen!
I just... want to talk to you.
Am I... not allowed even that?
Translation: Yukari Murase-Louden
Editing: Riley Dalton
Quality Check: Ashley Barboza
Translation Check: Elizabeth Ellis